

Diana Marcela Lizarazo Pereira

Address: Kra 94 #131d-08, Bogotá D.C, Colombia Email: dmlizarazop@unal.edu.co | Telephone: +57 312 316 3430

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A committed, responsible, active and leader with facility in work on teams and group management. Interested in theoretical and experimental work in cognition, with significant expertise in statistical analysis. Experienced in experimental design, strategic planning, data collection, data management and data analysis. Experience in working with vulnerable populations and teaching in poverty contexts. Dreamer, lover of language learning and cultural exchanges.

EDUCATION

02/2013 - present (Prom 2018)

Universidad Nacional de Colombia | Bogotá, Colombia

B.A Psychology

Thesis Title: Language influence of implicit measures in social Psychology.

Supervisor: Ricardo M. Tamayo

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

06/2017 - 12/2017

Purdue University | West Lafayette, United States

Research Practice

Title: Effects of Frequency and Emotional Valence in Word Processing by Native and Foreign English

Speakers

Supervisor: Felicia Roberts & Ricardo Tamayo

06/2017 - 12/2017

Purdue University | West Lafayette, United States

Research Assistant- cognition laboratory

Supervisor: Robert Proctor

08/2017 - 12/2017

Purdue University | West Lafayette, United States

Research Assistant -Social cognition and social Justice Laboratory

Supervisor: Erin Hennes

11/2017

Purdue University | West Lafayette, United States

Shadow - EEG Laboratory

Supervisor: Keisha Novak

03/2016 - present

Universidad Nacional de Colombia | Bogotá, Colombia

Research Assistant – Implicit cognition laboratory

Supervisor: Ricardo Tamayo Osorio

08/2015 - present

Universidad Nacional de Colombia | Bogotá, Colombia

Research Assistant – Learning and evolution of human and animal behaviour

Supervisor: German Gutierrez Dominguez

UNIVERSITY EMPLOYMENT

03/2018-04/2017

Orienteer | Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Choco, Colombia

- Vocational orientation to teenagers
- Teaching textual and image analysis
- Interaction with vulnerable population

02/2017-06/2017

Teacher Assistant | Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Bogotá, Colombia

- Supervises learning and evolution of human and animal behaviour laboratory.
- Organises weekly seminar.
- Construction and qualification of exams and workshops.

05/2013 - 02/2015

Typist | Universidad Nacional de Colombia, City, Country

- Typing of documents
- Management of confidential information

02/2016 - 06/2016

Academic Tutor | Universidad Nacional de Colombia , Bogotá , Colombia

- Tutoring new students in the Psychology department
- Mentoring and counselling during the transition to university's life

VOLUNTEERING

06/2017-06/2017

Vacation Bible school (VBS) Calvary, West Lafayette, United States

- Group management
- Kid's recreational activities

06/2016-07/2016

Summer volunteer | AIESEC, Bogotá, Colombia

- Receiving and accompaniment to foreigners
- Realizing welcome and integration activities
- Carry out sightseeing tours in the city

ABILITIES:

- Working on teams
- o Leadership
- Creativity
- Easy learning
- o Learning of English, German, French and Portuguese

SKILLS:

- o Interpersonal social skills.
- o Facility to verbal and writing communication.
- o Identify, analyse and improve processes.
- o Find innovate solutions for potential problems.
- o Flexibility and adaptability in different environments.
- o Passion for work, sunny disposition, and upbeat, positive attitude.
- o Software knowledge: SPSS, Lertap, Office, inquisit, Endnote.
- Data cleaning
- Data Collection and Analysis
- Tutoring and presenting

KNOWLEDGE:

- o Evolution of behaviour
- Human and animal learning
- o Implicit and explicit learning
- Methods of experimental research
- Cognitive process
- Psycholinguistics
- Human action control

LANGUAGES:

- Spanish Mother language
- English C1
- German B1
- French B2
- Portuguese A1

PUBLICATIONS

Arias, N., Lizarazo, D., Paez, D., & Zambrano, J. "DISCRIMINACIÓN VISUAL EN RATAS Y EFECTOS DE DOS FORMAS DE APRENDIZAJE POR CORRECCIÓN". Laberinto Journal, Accepted and forthcoming.

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

Effects of frequency and emotional valence in native and foreign English speakers. Purdue Linguistics, literature and second language conference 2018, speaker, Purdue University, March 2-4 2018. IN, USA.

PROFESIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

Purdue linguistics association (PLA)

REFERENCES:

Robert Proctor, Distinguished professor in the department of psychological sciences at Purdue University rproctor@purdue.edu +1 (765) 494-0784

Felicia Roberts, Professor; School Associate Head in the Brian lamb school of communication at Purdue university <u>froberts@purdue.edu</u> +1 (765) 494-3323

Ricardo M. Tamayo, Professor in the department of psychology at Universidad Nacional de Colombia rmtamayoos@unal.edu.co +57 313 222 7637

German A. Gutierrez, Professor in the department of psychology at Universidad Nacional de Colombia <u>gagutierrezd@unal.edu.co</u> +57